### **Davey Mason**

Designer | Developer | daveymason@outlook.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Developer with 2+ years designing, developing, maintaining and updating websites and web apps.

Natural **problem solver** with a strong passion for **design and performance**. A **quick learner**, solid attitude with international experience who is **creative**, **productive** and keeps on top of the latest technological trends.

Demonstrates strong critical thinking, decision making, time management, multi-tasking, and communication skills.

#### **CORE PROFICIENCIES**

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Php | MySQL | Bootstrap | jQuery | WordPress | React.js | Node.js | SASS UI/UX | OOP | Functional | Material Design | Responsive Design | Mobile First | Agile SEO | NPM | Domains & Hosting | Web Security | Git & GitHub | Google Suite | PC building & repair

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Web Developer | SERVE, Remote, Online

2021-Present

A volunteer position where I could use my web skills to help a worthy cause.

- Decreased the loading time from 11 seconds down to under 2 seconds.
- Secured the site and ensured it was GDPR compliant.
- Improved the SEO, integrated with the Google suite and educated staff how to make the most of their site.
- Used CSS to style portions of the website and implemented a host of changes from marketers and other stakeholders.

#### Web Developer | Fat Head Solutions, Remote, Online

2020-Present

A client facing role where I help clients identify and implement a wide range of digital solutions.

- Design and develop beautiful responsive websites that are secure and load quickly across all devices.
- Built large complex websites with premium content hidden behind a paywall and configured user roles.
- Integrated third party payment solutions to the clients request and content.

#### **Web Developer** | <u>DEITG I.T. Generalists</u>, Cork, Ireland.

2018-2019

Started as a web designer and ended managing the web department.

- Designed and developed over 50 websites using WordPress, Php, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap & jQuery.
- Worked with a senior developer on the front-end of large web apps using CSS & CakePhp.
- Worked in an Agile environment & reported to the managing director, I eliminated technical debt, set up automated maintenance and revamped the web department into a profitable, easy to manage profit making sector of the company.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science in Applied Physics & Instrumentation.

Cork Institute of technology.

[2011 - 2014]

# Bachelor of Science in Digital technology & Design.

Dublin Institute of technology.

[2017 - 2018]

#### Post Graduate Module in Software Development.

Open University, Online & Remote.

[2019]

## Full-stack Coding Bootcamp

NuCamp,
Online & Remote.

[2021]





